# **SREEREMYA S**

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER

+45 71830103 | sreeremyapratheesh@gmail.com | Sønderborg, Denmark | linkedin.com/in/sreeremyasreeharan

#### **SUMMARY**

Web Developer with 6 years of experience specializing in Angular and UI development. Transitioned from software testing to front-end development, blending strong technical expertise with a creative edge from a background in animation. A team-oriented developer passionate about building responsive, user-friendly web applications. Actively looking to expand into Full-Stack Development.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Languages: Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Frontend Frameworks: AngularJs, Angular, Ionic, ReactJs
- SDLC Methodologies: DevOps, Agile, Waterfall
- Libraries: Angular Material, Syncfusion, Bootstrap, PrimeNG, AG Grid, Angular Core UI, Leaflet.js, Chart.js
- Tools: Jira, HP ALM, Rally
- API Testing & Development: Postman, SoapUI, Swagger
- IDE: Visual Studio, Eclipse
- Deployment: Git, Bitbucket, WinSCP, Db2, Notepad++
- Design Tools: Canva, Figma, Inkscape, Corel Draw, Adobe XD, Photoshop, After Effects, Premiere

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Self-Learner: Continuously seeks to improve and expand knowledge independently.
- Innovative: Thinks creatively to develop unique solutions and improve processes.
- Collaborative: Works effectively with team members to achieve common goals.
- Effective Communicator: Clearly conveys ideas and technical concepts to diverse audiences.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Relocation to Denmark**

2023 June - Till date

Relocated to Denmark to support my husband's career, now eager to leverage my web development skills in new and exciting opportunities.

# Frontend Developer (Domain: Public utility (Energy ) ) 2022 – 2023

UST Global Technology Services Pvt. Ltd. (India)

- **Sempra**: Developed a website solution for monitoring electrical grid data, integrating **Chart.js** and **AG-grid** for visualization, and collaborated with cross-functional teams under CTO guidance.
- Nissan: Built a website for employees to manage customer car purchases and agreements, added multilingual functionality, and implemented Redux for state management.

#### Frontend Developer (Domain: IoT, Fleet Management)

2017 - 2021

Tata Consultancy Services (India)

- McKinsey & Company: Developed IoT-enabled websites for inventory and customer path tracking using Chart.is and real-time updates with WebSockets.
- Postnord: Created an IoT fleet management solution, including multilingual functionality, AzureAD SSO, and reactive forms. Worked with DevOps for cloud deployment and collaborated with design teams for user-friendly interfaces.
- **Donaldson:** Led a team developing IoT solutions for fleet monitoring, implementing chart visualizations, **AzureAD SSO**, and reusable web components.

# Software Tester/Test Analyst(Domain:Professional Service and Banking)

2012 - 2016

Tata Consultancy Services (India)

• Conducted E2E testing for a US-based bank using **SoAP UI, DB2,** and **mainframe** tools. Managed project estimation and progress reporting in waterfall models.

#### FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

#### Mission Planner for Robot (Aug 2021)

 Developed an interface for assigning tasks to robots via a handheld device using Angular 7 and Bootstrap.

# IoT Dashboard (Oct 2021)

 Created an interface for visualizing real-time and archived sensor data on users' mobile devices using Ionic, MQTT, and WebSocket.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor in Animation 2009 - 2011

Bharathidasan University

• B.Sc. in Animation provides a creative foundation, allowing me to bring a unique visual perspective to web development, especially in UI/UX design and building engaging, user-friendly interfaces.

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

#### · Languages:

- English: Professional proficiency
- Malayalam: Native speaker
- Danish: Beginner, currently learning

#### Hobbies:

- Exploring nature and its beauty with friends and family
- Singing karaoke
- Cooking new dishes
- Playing and learning with my toddler
- Socializing and networking by joining art and sports groups